A Guide to the Ellen Glasgow Papers 1929-1941
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Ellen Glasgow 1929-1941
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
4330
This collection consists of ca. 20 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of James Southall Wilson, 1953 June 6.
Scope and Content Information
The papers consist of letters to James Southall Wilson concerning her literary pursuits and mentioning Starke Young, Stringfellow Barr, and Allen Tate. There is also a letter, 1933 August 2, from Tate to Wilson regarding Tate's criticism of Glasgow's early work.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1929 Feb 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1929 Dec 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, [1932] June 24; ALS, 2 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, [1932 Sept 19]; ALS, 3 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1933 Mar 22; ALS, 3 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, [1933 June 8]; ALS, 2 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1933 June 18; ALS, 1 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1933 June 27; ALS, 2 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, [1933 July 12]; TLS, 1 p. with envelope
  - Allen Tate to James Southall Wilson, 1933 Aug 2; TLS, 1 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1933 Aug 28; TLS, 1 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1933 Sept 15; TLS, 1 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1936 July 15; TLS, 2 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, [l936 July 28]; ALS, 2 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1936 Dec 7; TLS, 2 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, [1936] Dec 19; ALS, 2 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1937 Jan 2; ALS, 1 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1940 Aug 2; ALS, 4 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, 1941 Mar 17; ALS, 3 p. with envelope
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Southall Wilson, [1941 Aug 25]; APCS